<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webgl on Black Thread Design</title>
    <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tags/webgl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webgl on Black Thread Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tags/webgl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Components and Helpers</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/2-components-helpers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/2-components-helpers/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations! You made it to Section 2! That means you know have a basic understanding of how to set up a three.js scene, how to make it animate, add textures, camera controls and even automatically resize along with the browser window.
In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a closer look at some of the components that make up three.js, as well as some of the helper objects.
We&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at how the various components fit together (inheritance) and take our first in depth animation of an object - the Object3D which is the base class for nearly everything in three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/1-0-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/1-0-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Strap in folks, it&amp;rsquo;s time to push some pixels!
Let&amp;rsquo;s get our first three.js scene up and running. When we are finished with chapters 1 and 2, we&amp;rsquo;ll have this glorious beast shining and rotating before us:

Follow along on Codepen I mentioned a few times in the introductory chapters that we&amp;rsquo;ll be using Codepen throughout these tutorials, and that you can either follow along there or create local files on your computer, but since I assume that lots of people are like me and skip introductory chapters, I should probably mention it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting help and reporting bugs</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/0-3-getting-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/0-3-getting-help/</guid>
      <description>{:.no_toc}
So you need help? What&amp;rsquo;s that? You are completely frustrated, about to tear your hair out with frustration? You are cursing this abomination of a library, casting it out, never to darken your hard drive again?
Well, I have some good news for you!
First, take a deep breath, go outside and pet some kittens or shout at them or whatever else relieves your tortured soul (seriously, don&amp;rsquo;t shout at kittens).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lights, Color, Action!</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/1-1-lights-color-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/1-1-lights-color-action/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll pick up here exactly where we left off in the last chapter. Here is the complete code so far:
// create a WebGLRenderer and set its width and height const renderer = new THREE.WebGLRenderer(); renderer.setSize( window.innerWidth, window.innerHeight ); // add the automatically created canvas element to the page document.body.appendChild( renderer.domElement ); // create a Scene const scene = new THREE.Scene(); // set up the options for a perspective camera const fov = 35; // fov = Field Of View const aspect = window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements for running a three.js scene</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/0-0-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/0-0-requirements/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a quick overview of what you need to get a basic three.js app working. Please take the time to read over the topics in the introduction (we&amp;rsquo;ll get to the pretty 3D stuff soon, I promise!).
WebGL In these tutorials, we are going to be focusing on the WebGLRenderer. As the name implies, this requires a WebGL enabled device. Not so long ago, this was something that we had to worry about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shapes and Transformations</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/1-5-shapes-transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/tutorials/1-5-shapes-transformations/</guid>
      <description>In this chapter, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a lighting quick look at some of the geometric shapes that are built into three.js. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen two of them, the Torus Knot from chapters 1.1 and 1.2, and the Box from Chapter 1.3.
We&amp;rsquo;ll also take a look at how to move them around (translate them), scale them up and down and rotate them. Collectively, along with the less common shear, these are known as transformations (technically, they are linear or affine transformations).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>