<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiments on Black Thread Design</title>
    <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experiments on Black Thread Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Circles Animation</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/circles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/circles/</guid>
      <description>Pretty circles with a pure CSS animation hover effect. They were originally intended for the front page of this site. I decided not to use them there since I wanted to showcase some WebGL, but I still think they look nice! They&#39;re fully responsive too, so go ahead and resize the browser window.  They were originally inspired by something I found on CodePen, however I can&#39;t find it again to provide proper attribution - so, thank you mystery coder for the inspiration!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codepen</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/codepen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/codepen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EscherSketch</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/eschersketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/eschersketch/</guid>
      <description>This is a prototype of an automatic hyperbolic art generator and educational tool. It creates a regular edge to edge tiling of the hyperbolic plane represented as a Poincaré disk, also known as a hyperbolic tesselation.  These were originally described by H. S. M. Coxeter, but were made famous by M.C. Escher in his series of Circle Limit woodcuts, back in the era when people were known only by their initials and surnames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribbons</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/ribbons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/experiments/ribbons/</guid>
      <description>Most browsers are unable to display thick lines with WebGL - the lines will always be rendered at 1px, no matter what the thickness is set to.  In this experiment the lines are generated as thin triangle strips, allowing for lines of any thickness.  Note that with this implementation, the thickness is a property of the geometry, so that if the camera zooms in the lines will get thicker.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>