<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hidden on Black Thread Design</title>
    <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hidden on Black Thread Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NFL Scouting App Test Page</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/nfl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/nfl/</guid>
      <description>Ratings Size  Athletic Ability  Foot Quickness / Setup  Dominant Hand Left Right Both  Release Quickness  Delivery  Mechanics  Arm Strength  Anticipation / Rhythm  Accuracy Short  Touch Short  Accuracy Long  Touch Long  Decision Making  Read Coverage/Go through Progression  Pocket Presence  Poise  Mobility  Throw on Move  Running Ability  Clutch Production  Ability to Win         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robot Dance</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/robot_dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/robot_dance/</guid>
      <description>Start with creating frames   Info Let&#39;s start by creating some frames. Each frame is a static pose that the robot can be in.
You can control the robot&#39;s head, shoulders and elbows. For each controllable joint, there are two axes of control, labelled pitch and yaw.
These control up/down and left/right motion.
Frames can either be grouped together, or added directly to the dance.
    # Head Left Shoulder Right Shoulder Left Elbow Right Elbow Add Frame         Create groups with multiple frames   Info Now that we&#39;ve created some frames, we can start to make an animation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robot Simulation</title>
      <link>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blackthreaddesign.com/hidden/robot/</guid>
      <description>Reset Randomize Run Simulation Show Grid Equation: y =   The field is a rectangle of width 1.4 metres and length 2 metres, the goal is 50cm wide and the centre of the table is at position (0, 0).
The ball has been randomly placed on the table at position (), which gives the above equation for a line going along the surface of the table through the ball.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>